传说中
Legend tells of a lord...
[Indistinct whispering]
上帝加冕最宅的人类
Crowned the nerdiest, uber-nerd of all nerds...
"陛下请起, 请您登上王座"
Arise, your majesty, and claim your throne!
[Indistinct whispering]
众宅之王
A king of the nerds.
但众神叛乱了.
But the gods rebelled.
Insolubrio necroma!
宅王被推翻了
The king was smote.
Nerdvana, 宅界圣殿被摧毁.
Nerdvana, the high seat of nerd-dom, was destroyed.
我将让使宅界一片火海
Man: I shall rain fire upon this land!
[Laughs evilly]
元老们秘密的逃到了这个圣地,
In secret, the elder nerds escaped to a new hallowed hall,
一个新的Nerdvana, 私下中
a new Nerdvana, where it is whispered
寻找新宅王开始了
that a search for a new king has begun...
一个新的宅王将要再次统治一切.
a new nerd to rule them all.
别老那么啰嗦, 真让我烦.
You always do this. I hate it.
我停不下来了
I can't make it stop.
别了, 停
Well, just stop. You k...
我还是自己来吧, 行不
no, no, look, I'm just gonna do it myself, all right?
OK, 开始
Okay. Now...
一个崭新的组织逐渐形成...
A new fellowship has formed...
你也被关在储物柜里过?
Did you get shoved in a locker, too?
11个绝世聪明...
11 more of the brainiest...
我试试把电容过载? 试试看.
- Can I overpower some capacitors? - Man: Let's do it.
怎么没有Linux系统?
Where is the linux machine?
游戏达人...
Gaming...
霜之哀伤!(wow武器)
Frostmournes!
别让老子搞死你们!
I could destroy each and every one of you.
魔幻与科幻控.
Fantasy and science-fiction-lovingest nerds in the world.
我在"创世界"中.(虚拟数字世界)
I'm actually inside tron.
企业号号将完暴千年隼号.(星级迷航与星球大战中的战舰)
The enterpri would beat the millennium falcon.
千年隼号可以绕着企业号画圈圈,
The falcon can fly circles around the enterprise,
特别是后者把所有能量转移到防护罩上之后.
especially when the latter is diverting all power to shields.
他们将在游戏中竞技知识与技巧...
They will compete in games of knowledge and skill...
想想下骑在扫帚飞行的时候计算距离,时间与重力.
Imagine calculating relativity while flying on a broomstick.
你真的有把握
Do you really think you can beat me
在cosplay角色扮演游戏中赢我?
in a larping and gaming challenge?
太天真了.
[Laughs] That's cute.
争相让世界级的专家刮目相看
Vying to impress the great nerd experts...
From around the world.
我们马上要跟那些专家一起工作了.
[Chanting] Nerds! Nerds! You're gonna be working for them pretty soon.
好宅. 我喜欢.
So nerdy. Love it.
但只有一人可以登上王座.
But only one can claim the throne.
坐上那个椅子前必将经历血雨腥风.
There's gonna be bloodshed to get to that chair.
仅一人可以戴上王冠.
Only one can wear the crown.
命悬一线
Lives hang in the balance.
我将砍倒并且毁灭每一个阻挡我的人!
I will slash through and destroy anyone who stands in my path!
砰! [机器人] 开始吧, 呆子们.
- Poof! - [Robotic voice] Let's do this, nerds.
只有一人可以成为...
Only one can be...
众宅之王!
King of the nerds!
Yeah!
哈哈哈哈哈!
Heh! Heh! Heh! Heh! Heh!
这个给力.
That's awesome.
哎.
Ahh.
[Dramatic music plays]
吃饱了好学习译.
Sync & corrections by No1 www.addic7ed.com.
- 这哥们毛孩儿 - 恩呢.
- That's a furry one. - Indeed.
我叫Brian, 我是个十足的书虫.
My name is Brian, and I'm a complete bookworm.
我将成为众宅之王
I'm gonna be king of the nerds
人人都爱穿着马甲的霍比特人.
because everybody loves a hobbit in a vest.
我叫Mary Kate.
My name is Mary Kate.
我正在学习航空航天工程.
I'm studying aerospace engineering.
我喜欢Cosplay.
I'm an avid costumer.
我主要扮成超级英雄, 但我也喜欢穿上我的小马驹套装.
I mostly costume superheroes, but I also can don my pony gear
因为我粉. (动漫)
because I'm a bronie.
抬起你的小马蹄!
Put your hoofs up!
他很激动呀!
- [Giggles] - He's very happy to be here.
我是Zachary Storch.
I'm Zachary Storch.
我是世界魔兽争霸玩家25强之一.
I'm one of the top 25 world of warcraft gamers on the planet.
宅要有激情.
Being a nerd is about passion.
宅是一种生活方式
Being a nerd is a way of life
因为史上最伟大的人
because the greatest people throughout all of history...
最伟大的人都宅.
the greatest people... were nerds.
[Laughs]
欢迎来到新的宅界Nerdvana!
Welcome to the new Nerdvana!
比之前所有都更大更宅!
Bigger and nerdier than ever before!
[Cheers and applause]
我叫Curtis. 我叫Bobby.
- I'm Curtis. - And I'm Bobby.
能见到这些我从小喜欢的宅元素在一起真是太幸福了.
I'm beyond stoked to meet the nerds I grew up loving.
你们将为10万元奖金
You will be competing for $100,000
与众宅之王的王冠而竞争.
and the right to be crowned king of the nerds.
[Cheers and applause]
10万元可以改变我的生活.
$100,000 is a life-changing amount of money.
我会用来买更大更好的火箭.
I could buy bigger rockets, better rockets.
我有一个梦想
One of my pipe dreams has always been
我想有个瀑布在家里.
that I want a waterfall in my house one day.
每一周, 你们会分组竞技,
Each week, you will compete, team against team,
宅王争霸
in a battle royale known as the Nerd War.
上一季, 第一个比赛是分组.
Now, last season, the first Nerd War was dividing into teams.
这季, 我们也从分组开始.
This season, we pick teams again.
你们要分成两组, 每组5人.
You will divide yourselves into two teams of five nerds each.
你们一共有11人, 所以会有一人剩下.
Now, there are 11 of you, and one of you will be left out.
说不准哦.
Or not.
今天的比赛, 我们从meta开始.
For today's war, we're going meta.
[Chuckles]
meta这个概念指的是"自我引用",
The concept of meta refers to self-reference,
所以一个meta游戏就是一个关于游戏的游戏.
so a meta game would be a game about a game.
上一季中的惊天大逆转,
Last season, in a stunning reversal,
最后一个落选的人有无上的权力, 因为你懂的
the last person picked had all of the power, because, as you know,
没有比没人要更宅的事儿了.
there is nothing nerdier than being picked last.
我们知道你们知道没有更宅的事儿了,
We know that you know that nothing is nerdier,
现在你们知道我们知道... 你们知道的事实.
and you now know that we know... That you know.
我们知道他们知道我们知道
We know that they know that we know
这次比赛会有个大变化.
that there's a twist to this challenge,
就是我们还不知道什么会发生.
and we have no idea what's gonna happen.
被剩下还算是宅吗?
Is being picked last still nerdy?
太没人性了.
It's an evil way to play a game.
第一个队长是...
The first team captain is...
Zachary!
给力.
Awesome.
Sylvanas的胜利!
Victory for Sylvanas!
Sylvanas是流亡的女妖皇后.
Sylvanas is the banshee queen of the forsaken.
第二个队长是...
The second team captain is...
- ...Chris! - Yes.
我是Chris Jackson, 我是我见过的最酷的人.
I'm Chris Jackson, and I am the coolest person I know.
我将成为众宅之王
I will be king of the nerds
因为我代表了工程师.
because I represent the engineering community.
没有工程师就没有企业号.
You can't make an enterprise without engineers.
没有工程师就不可以瞬间传送.
You can't do teleportation without engineers.
不可以制作光剑.
You can't make a lightsaber without engineers.
我们统治世界.
We rule the world.
Zachary和Chris, 你们需要负责选第一个队友.
Zachary and Chris, you get to make the first picks.
你们有两个小时的时间去探索Nerdvana
You now have two hours to explore Nerdvana
去了解每个人的长处和弱点.
and get to know each other's strengths and weaknesses.
让这场众宅智慧的较量
Let the nerd war of wits...
开始
Commence!
[Cheers and applause]
Yeah!
Nicole: Oh, my God!
这是世界上最炫酷的地方了.
This is the coolest place ever.
[Laughing] Whoa!
Nicole: 这是Celeste!(上季冠军)
Nicole: Oh, my gosh! It's Celeste!
打开门后看到的一切
Opening the door and looking at Nerdvana...
太震惊了
it was just like... [Imitates explosion]
快过来
Oh, my God! Come here! Come here! [Screams]
Zack: 这儿有两把霜之哀伤!
Zack: Oh, my! There's... there's two frostmournes!
Frostmournes!
看到那些剑的时候我太激动了, 我拿起来
I am so psyched to see all the swords I can pick up
就像是拥有了勇士的力量.
and just, like, be the power of the warrior.
[Laughs]
好, 听我说.
Okay, here we go.
星际迷航还是星球大战好?
"Star Trek" or "Star Wars"?
不! 两个没法一起比较!
No! You can't compare!
可以的, 你能!
Yes, you can!
我叫Kayla.
My name's Kayla.
我有空间研究的博士学位.
I have a master's degree in space studies.
谁粉迷航?
Who all is on the trek side?
星际迷航要比星球大战好
"Star Trek" is better than "Star Wars"
因为星际迷航是讲述探索,
because "Star Trek" is about exploration,
我的梦想, 我的目标, 我的激情就是把人类送到火星.
and my dream, my goal, and my passion is to send humans to Mars.
你想把这些整在一起? "萤火虫" (科幻电电视剧)
You want to bring it all together? "Firefly."
[All cheering]
谁会关心谁先开火?
Who cares who shot first?
Nicole: Oh, 这儿有个时光机!
Nicole: Oh, my God! It's a tardis!
这是个无线电时光屋!
It's a radioshack tardis!
Zack: 大家, 无线电时光屋!
Zack: Guys, a radioshack tardis!
Chris: 这个房子里最酷的就是这个无线电实验室了
Chris: The coolest thing in the house is a radioshack lab
在一个灰色时光机里,
那里有机械工程师所需的一切.
where it had everything any mechanical engineer would ever need.
Katie: 这里简直是顶级科学家的梦想.
Katie: This is a rocket scientist's dream.
时光机是神秘博士的飞船(Doctor Who, 英剧神秘博士).
The tardis is doctor who's ship.
是"时间与宇宙相对维度"的缩写.
It stands for "Time And Relative Dimension In Space."
我为什么会先拿个计算器看?
Why did I look at the calculator first?
我叫Jack, 我的专业是药品与生物工程.
My name is Jack, and I study medicine and bioengineering.
怎么没有Linux系统?
[Chuckling] Where is the linux machine?
我比较内向, 但大家都知道我会说唱.
I am introverted, but I have been known to rap.
女孩子们都会着魔
[Rapping] ♪ make them girls go loco
当他们看到我炫耀周期表
♪ when they see me bust a move on the periodic table ♪
这并不简单, 但这个很书呆
♪ It ain't easy, but it's nerdy ♪
是的, 这些是化学
♪ And, yeah, there's some chemistry ♪
如果你想学就跟我重复
♪ But if you want to learn it, then repeat after me ♪
氢, 氦, 锂, 铍, 硼, 碳
Hydrogen, helium, lithium, beryllium, boron, carbon...
碳... 饿... 你懂就行了. o(╯□╰)o
car... uh... Yeah, so... Oh, yeah, but you get the gist.
[Laughter]
靠, 咱们在墙上!
Holy crap! That's all of us!
Katie: 我喜欢这个造型, 光剑装甲机器人
Katie: I love how I'm a lightsaber-wielding robot
手持西奥多·罗斯福木偶.
with a Theodore Roosevelt puppet.
我叫Katie. 机械工程学学士.
My name is Katie. Got my bachelor's in mechanical engineering.
我所有大学课程都是关于制造宇宙飞船,
All of my graduating class are building spaceships,
然后我决定, "我该做几个玩偶了."
and I was like, "I'm gonna build puppets now."
所以我现在在"芝麻街"实习.
So I am currently an intern at "Sesame Street."
大家! 我们只有两个小时了解每个人.
Guys! We have two hours to learn everyone's life story.
我还没玩够呢.
I'm not done nerding out yet.
Mary Kate: 进入屋子以后, 我们围坐在一个圆桌
Mary Kate: After going into the house, we sat at a round table
然后讲关于我们个人的特长与成绩.
and talked about, like, what our credentials were.
过去的两年, 我在一个火箭设计的小组担任项目经理.
I've been project manager of my rocket-design team for the past two years.
实际上我赢过一个NASA比赛
Actually, I won a contest by NASA
挑选出杰出爱好者, 我是第一哦.
to pick their greatest fan, and I was that winner.
[Laughter]
每个人在各自领域都非常杰出.
Everybody's such an expert at their thing.
太吓人了.
It's intimidating.
我好像哪里见过你.
Yeah, I think I've seen you somewhere.
一些人在网上认识我, 我的网名"JWittz"
Some people know me as "JWittz" on the Internet.
我是宠物小精灵专家
- I'm a pokémon master. - Ohh! Yeah!
我叫Josh
I'm Josh.
我在YouTube有个宠物小精灵频道.
I run a pokémon-centered YouTube channel.
目前为止, 我有超过500万点击量.
Right now, I have about 50 million views.
并且, 我参加世界级的
On top of that, I've also competed on the world level
宠物小精灵交易棋牌游戏.
for the pokémon trading card games.
我知道宠物小精灵"不太流行了"
I know pokémon at one point became "not cool."
但并没有停止我对其的喜爱.
I just never stopped caring.
很高兴认识大家.
Nice to meet you all.
我不知道怎么接了.
God. I don't know how to follow that.
我是Nicole. 化学专业.
I'm Nicole. I got my bachelor's degree in chemistry.
我的方向是钒345复合物
My field of study was synthesis and characterizations
的合成与表征
of vanadium 345 complexes.
但因为我是个化学家... 我可能是个大靶子
But the fact that I'm a chemist... that puts a huge target on my back.
我可能是超级音乐宅吧
I'm probably the resident uber music nerd here.
我敲了不知道多长时间的鼓了.
I've been drum major for God knows how long.
我开始先让自己看起来比较弱小.
So I'm gonna kind of make myself look a little weak at first.
我敢打赌, 我是这里唯一一个可以从后往前写字的人.
Bet I'm the only one here that can write backwards.
可能之后我会泄密, "对了, 顺便说下",
Maybe later on, I might divulge, like, "hey, by the way",
我是无机物化学家, 我懂这些.
I'm an inorganic chemist, so I know my stuff."
我叫Xander
My name is Xander.
- Chris: 领结不错. - 这是别上去的.
- Chris: Nice bow-tie. - It's a clip-on.
[All groan] I know. Aah!
我叫Xander, 我是个"基情"玩家!
My name is Xander, and I am a gay gamer!
G-A-Y-M-E-R, Gaymer
So we go by G-A-Y-M-E-R. Gaymer.
我很多东西都懂一点儿
I know a little about a lot of things.
我就像是个瑞士大呆兵, 我会现场表演.(larper, live action role play)
I'm like a Swiss army nerd. I'm a larper.
这是我的泡沫弯刀!
I've got my foam cutlass!
我是男高音...
I'm a countertenor...
[Vocalizing]
我喜欢戏剧...
And a drama nerd...
这是我喜欢表演的角色.
[Japanese accent] This is a character that I love to play.
这是个愤怒的日本人.
This is angry Japanese man.
我是日本控.
I'm a japanophile.
你会讲日语吗.
[Speaking Japanese]
会滴.
Ahh!
[Speaking Chinese]
意思是, "大家好, 我叫Kelsey"
That means, "hello, my name is Kelsey."
学习外语实际上是我的最大爱好.
Learning languages is actually a big hobby of mine.
我会讲中文, 日语, 西语, 英语.
I speak Chinese, Japanese, Spanish, and English.
我是英语教学专业研究生.
I'm getting my master's in teaching English as a second language.
[Speaking Japanese]
"我要成为众宅之王."
"I want to be king of the nerds."
这将是非常非常 "suzushii desu."
That would be very, very "suzushii desu."
酷
You know, very cool.
我们接下来怎么该做什么?
So, how are we gonna do this, guys?
我们就闲聊, 然后让队长做决定?
Are we just gonna talk and let the captains do their thing?
Chris: 这个决定很有趣.
Chris: This is an interesting decision.
我要告诉你我的所有信息.
So I'm going to tell you my full background.
我决定告诉Zack
I decided to tell Zack what I am.
我是个化学家.
I'm a chemist.
Yeah.
领导才能方面, Chris很可能是个很好的领袖.
From a leadership standpoint, Chris would be a stronger leader,
但是Zack有我所缺少的.
but Zack has what I don't have.
我需要一个人来弥补我的不足...
I needed someone that balances my skills...
就是你.
and that's you.
你数学很强?
Do you have a lot of math skills?
我跟你一起进4强怎么样. 好哇.
- So, what I'd like to do is try to go final four with you. - I'd be okay with that.
希望Zack不要告诉别人我是化学家.
Hopefuy, Zack doesn't tell anybody I'm a chemist.
如果他说了, 我们的联盟...
If he does, this alliance...
就没了.
Poof! Gone.
这个会发光还是咋地?
Does it light up or something?
Kayla, 你关于重启"星际迷航"有什么想法.
Kayla, your opinion on the reboot "Star Trek."
这是当你允许星球大战粉丝
It's what happens when you give a "Star Wars" fan
批评星际迷航时会发生的.
permission over "Star Trek."
你能以把一个宇宙飞船放到TMD海里去!
You can't put a starship under the freakin' ocean!
首战是要选队
The first Nerd War is to pick teams.
Zack是队长, Chris是另一个.
Zack is one captain, and Chris is the other one.
我们都在讨论, 这个大变化最后会是什么.
We've all been, like, talking, what this twist could be at the end,
因为我们知道这不可能跟去年一样.
'cause we know it can't be the same as last year's.
会不会先让我们选人
What if they're making us pick
最后剩下那个人可以自由选择队?
and then the person who's left out picks the teams?
实际上, 我也是这么想的.
Actually, that's kind of what I was thinking of.
我们不确定这个大变化会不会是根本就没变化.
We're not exactly sure if the twist is that there is no twist,
太复杂了.
so things are getting kind of complicated.
别人在哪... Zack在哪?
Where's the other... where's Zack?
显然, 我会先选你.
Obviously, you're the person I want to pick first.
你觉着接下来我们应该选谁,
Who do you think is the person we should pick next,
如果我先选你了?
- if I pick you first? - It'd probably be...
叫什么来着? 对了.
- What's his face? - Yep.
我和Zack有个计划.
Going into the Nerd War, Zack and I have a plan.
谁会是最后剩下的?
Who would be the last one picked?
我觉着会是Kelsey.
I almost think Kelsey.
只要没有SB搅局, 我们就安全.
As long as there's no, like, crazy monkey wrench, we're good.
我跟你说过我的职业是什么吗?
Do I mention what my actual profession is?
咱们现在就这样. 好.
- Let's keep that for now. - Okay.
好的. Cool.
- All right. - Cool.
集合
[Alarm blaring] Calling all nerds!
比赛马上就要开始了
A Nerd War of wits is about to commence!
Xander: 现在要开始选人了. 每一个吊丝的噩梦.
Xander: And now it's time to pick teams. This is every nerd's nightmare.
[Exhales nervously]
Chris and Zack!
Curtis.
- They're right there.
- [Laughs]
I'm sorry.
[Laughter]
Chris, Zack, 来披上你们队的斗篷.
Chris and Zack, join us and don your team cloaks.
Josh: Wow. [Laughs]
你们开始选择队友
You will pick your teammates
把斗篷披在队友的肩上.
by placing your team cloaks upon their shulders.
现在,　你们用经典的剪刀石头布
Now, you will engage in a spirited rock-paper-scissors
来决定谁先开始
for the right to go first.
Ck: 有无穷多个
Ck: There is a significant amount of just ways
去操作控制别人的策略.
you can kind of subtly manipulate someone.
剪刀, 石头, 布, 出手.
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot.
就这样, １, 2, 3,　出手.
As in, 1, 2, 3, go. Okay. That'll work.
我觉着有可能
I was kind of maybe hoping just a little bit
我这样跟他说
that if I did that... rock, paper, scissors...
他潜意识中会觉着, "我应该出石头".
that maybe, subconsciously, he'd be like, "I should pick rock."
Ohh. All right.
布包石头.
Covers rock. All right.
你的策略是什么?
What is your strategy?
我需要选择一个
I need to pick someone right now
可以弥补我的不足的人.
who really complements my weaknesses.
你可以开始了.
You may proceed.
[Sighs]
Nicole: 如果他按照原计划,
Nicole: I knew I was the first one being picked,
我相信我会是第一个被选中的.
so as long as he sticks to the plan, we're good.
- Aah! - [Laughs]
谢谢!
Yellow! Yellow! Thank you!
Zack第一个选择了Nicole, 让我感到很意外
Once Zack picked Nicole, it was kind of a shock to me
因为她一点儿也不出众
because she didn't really stand out.
我本以为他会选择一个高端的工程师, 但Nicole凭啥?
I thought he'd go more for the hard-core engineer, but Nicole?
Chris, 轮到你选了.
Chris, it's your turn to make your first pick.
Chris: 我要组一个均衡形的团队. 我需要一个游戏达人.
Chris: I need a well-rounded team. I need a gamer on my team.
我需要有一个人善于表演, 一个电工.
I need a performer on my team and an electrician on my team.
我该选谁呢?
And how am I supposed to pick and choose?
跟我头发很配.
Matches my hair.
Nicole.
[Indistinct whispering]
这个是Zack决定的, 我也没什么意见.
This was Zack's decision, but I'm okay with it.
我会先按照计划行事.
I'll stick to the plan for now.
Nicole: 欢迎加入黄队.
- Nicole: Come join the yellow side. - Whoo.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
我还没被选. 开始有点儿紧张了.
I'm not picked yet. Starting to get a little nervous.
我现在有点儿宠物小精灵的感觉.
I feel like a pokémon with a special condition.
Katie, 你可以选人了.
Katie, you may make your pick.
傻站在这里太糟糕了
It's just an awful feeling just standing there
不知道花落谁家, 自己会不会落选.
and not knowing if you're gonna get picked or not.
- Ah! - Jack.
Xander: 斗篷每抖一下,
Xander: Every clink of the cloak,
我就感觉会披在我身上.
you think that it's gonna be laid upon you.
但并没有.
- And then it wasn't. - Brian.
然后我默念, "选我, 选我, 选我!"
I'm just going, "please, please, please... pick me."
然后他就选了!
And he does!
Yeah!
他把他那灵巧的手臂环保在我伟岸的身躯.
He manages to get those short, little arms around my big, tall body.
Josh, 你开始选了.
Josh, make your pick.
Kelsey: 我本以为我会被秒选.
Kelsey: I kind of thought I'd get picked sooner.
我觉着我的特长独一无二.
I thought what I have is kind of unique,
中文有句话, [木办法]
but the Chinese have a saying, you know [Speaking Chinese]
意思是, "木办法"
And that literally means "there's nothing else that can be done."
Oh! Oh, God.
还剩下俩人
And then there were two.
大家, 我并不知道这个大变化是什么.
Okay, guys, I don't know the twist.
Chris: 在Kelsey和Kayla之间很难抉择
Chris: Choosing between Kelsey and Kayla is very difficult
上一季最后就有一个.
because last season, there was a twist to the nerd challenge.
Bobby和Chrtis知道我们知道上季的改变
Bobby and Curtis know that we know there's a twist
并且他们还特别指出了
to that challenge, and they told us,
所以这次会发生什么很让我紧张.
so it's unnerving what's about to happen.
我可能会崩溃.
If we get broken up, it's fine.
紫队, 请选择最后一个队员.
Purple team, you may make your final pick.
木办法
[Speaking Chinese]
被剩下的感觉太受伤了.
When you're left out, it really does hurt.
你本以为找到了知己
You know, you think you found your friends,
但你的知己并不把你当作朋友.
and then your friends don't always turn out to be your friends.
心情五味杂陈
It's a very complex way to feel.
Brian: 我为Kelsey感到难过.
Brian: I feel a little bit bad for Kelsey.
但Kelsey是个未知数.
On the other hand, Kelsey's the big question now.
我们并不清楚他有什么特别之处.
We don't know what kind of power, if any, she's gonna have.
大大的问号.
It's all a big mystery.
- Kelsey. - Yeah.
上一季, 最后落选的人
Last season, the person who was not picked for either team
有至高的权利.
was given all the power.
因为没有什么比没人要更宅的了.
Because there's nothing nerdier than not getting picked.
是的, 我知道.
Yes, sir. I'm familiar with this.
很受伤吧.
It hurts. Right?
很疼, 我们知道.
- It does. - We've been there.
但是还有.
But here's the thing.
还有一个比没人要更宅的, 你们知道是什么吗?
Do you the one thing that is even nerdier than not getting picked?
什么?
What?
什么也没有!
- Nothing! - [Chuckles]
没有什么比剩下更宅的了!
Nothing is nerdier than not getting picked!
所以Kelsey
So, you, Kelsey...
你有无上的权力!
Have all the power!
实际上, 比上季的更大.
In fact, you have even more power.
是的.
That's right.
现在你可以选择
Because now you have to choose
任意一位选手, 永远从Nerdvana消失.
who you would like to see banished from Nerdvana right now for good.
大家好!
Hey, everyone!
现在Kelsey, 你要选择
Now, you, Kelsey, have to choose
你想从Nerdvana淘汰谁.
who you would like to see banished from Nerdvana right now for good.
大家面面相觑...
We're all just looking at each other like...
大家!
Hey, everyone! [Giggles]
世上最惨.
Worst... Twist... Ever.
你要送谁回家?
Who would you choose to send home?
命悬一线.
Lives hang in the balance.
本女王大权在手, 梦想成真.
It's like a dream come true 'cause I've always wanted to be queen. You get power.
我可以听到我的心在"砰砰砰"的跳.
I could just feel my heart go, you know, "pow-pow-pow-pow-pow."
我掌握着每个人的命运.
Your lives hang in my balance.
我最后没有选她,
I was the last one to betray her by not picking her,
她可能会报复我.
so I'm in jeopardy of going home.
我该选...
I am going to go with...
根据去年的情况,
Based on data from last season,
聪明的选手会被早早淘汰.
it seems that the smart people tend to be kicked out quickly.
所以我有危险.
That makes me a target.
Nicole.
无意冒犯, 多一个少一个Nicole也没什么区别.
No offense. We could lose Nicole and not really notice.
不好意思.
I do apologize.
Curtis: 好吧, Nicole, 跟大家告别.
Curtis: All right, Nicole, say your goodbyes.
我现在想法很乱.
There's so many coulda, woulda, shouldas going in my head right now.
Thanks.
或许我不应该那么低调.
Maybe I should have said my strengths.
没想到会那么快就回家了.
I didn't think I'd be going home this quickly.
Oops. [Chuckles]
Zack: 全完了.
Zack: This meta thing screwed everything up.
我和Nicole的联盟是赢得冠军的关键.
My alliance with Nicole was going to help me in this competition.
我现在真的不想离开,
At the same time, I sure didn't want to go home,
so I'm happy, but I'm not happy.
So, this is...
A frustrating thing.
Nicole, while you will not be
crowned king of the nerds...
- Curtis?
- Hm?
You know, there technically
is something nerdier
than not being picked.
Katie: We have another twist.
Whooooooo.
It's nerdier to be kicked out by
somebody who wasn't even on a team.
Bobby, you're right.
[Laughs] Stop the presses!
[Exhales deeply]
That means, Nicole...
You are the nerdiest
of all nerds!
Oh, my God.
And you have won
this Nerd War of wits!
Whoo-hoo!
Thank you for
scaring the bejesus out of me.
It's just our job.
Nicole, you will now choose
the winning team.
You will be joining that team.
Oh, gosh.
I'm gonna have to go...
back to my home team.
- The gold team.
- I want to join the gold team.
Gold team... You have
won this Nerd War!
Yeah!
Nicole coming back is like one
of my favorite pokémon items...
the revive.
She comes right back up from
the ashes and joins the fight,
and I am so glad she chose
to come back to our team.
You are also going to
have to pick someone
from the winning team
to go to the losing team.
I'll trade it with you, Kelsey.
Understandable.
Hey, Kelsey, how do you like
my reversal charm?
Isn't it so cool?
Curtis: Purple team,
as the losers of this Nerd War,
you are in peril.
Two of your members are going to
be selected to go to the Nerd-Off.
You will be picking
one of those two people.
Gold team will be selecting
the other person.
You have 24 hours to decide.
And while you're at it,
name your teams.
Good luck!
Zack: [Laughing] Oh yeah!
Meta.
- Jack: All right.
- Whoo-hoo!
We have endured.
I am quite relieved
that I have endured.
Zack: We have completely triumphed,
and we are the gold team.
So, so happy!
- Nicole, I was, like, so worried.
- I'm shaking.
You can't touch us, purple.
We're safe.
Kayla: [Sighs] Couch time.
Having two teammates
go into the Nerd-Off...
it sucks.
Can I say "sucks"? [Laughs]
Well, I'll start by saying "welcome
to the team. We love you."
I didn't mean, you know,
to condemn everyone, but...
No, it's fine.
We love you! It's the game.
Kelsey: There's a good chance I'm
gonna be in the Nerd-Off tomorrow.
I jumped from, you know,
the frying pan into the fire.
I think the first question
we got to think is,
- how are they going to look at...
- Who are they gonna pick?
Mary Kate: All right, they've got
three science people on their team...
Zack: So we don't want to
take one of those out, do we?
Well, I mean, do we want to?
'Cause we know
they're gonna put in Kelsey.
Josh: You think so? Yes.
I honestly think
they're gonna send in Kelsey.
She's kind of reserved,
kind of quiet.
She thinks outside the box
a lot.
I kind of compare myself
to a mongoose
because they're cute, they're
Fluffy, and they're vicious.
I don't know whether we need to
take out their smartest player.
Chris is pretty bright.
The one thing I do know is
that Zack will get his way.
I am moderately nervous.
He's either gonna choose me
or he's going to choose
one of the creative types.
I wish I was not the team
captain for the first Nerd War.
Because of that,
I have a huge target on my back.
He's a very analytical person.
He does not have
a lot of creative skills.
What's the heart, you know?
Like, where can we...
well, it'll either be
Chris or Katie.
I'm intimidated
by any of the competitors
that have a knowledge
of science or math
because it is a realm
that I just don't understand.
I'm gonna do a stat table.
So, let's see...
science, engineering, math...
We made a stat sheet
for everybody
because I rank algorithms
for a living.
Does Brian play
video and/or board games?
Actually, we could go
much farther than this.
I could show my partial
rank-list preference algorithms
and things like that.
But I can't show off too much.
Word might get out.
This is why I'm glad I'm in
the company of numbers people.
Yeah, numbers are pretty much
all I do. [Laughs]
Brian: I think that
whoever the gold team picks...
it's kind of irrelevant
to who we pick.
The other, kind of "random" way
that we could do it
is to not talk about it
and then just vote tomorrow.
Honestly, I kind of like the
idea of just voting tomorrow.
Xander:
I feel like the purple team...
we are level-headed
about how we feel,
how we want the game
to be played.
Chris: Okay, so, then let's say
tomorrow's vote is up to us...
choose our own adventure, pretty
much, for this round only.
Xander: But when it comes down
to it, we're gonna find out
where people's allegiances lie
in our team.
No hard feelings.
- [Rooster crows]
- Curtis: All nerds to the throne room!
Nicole: Oh, my...
Brian: Today is our first
Nerd-Off, and it will be somebody
from the purple team against
somebody from the purple team.
It's like
Bruce Wayne's hall of armor.
Josh: It really feels like
this regal chamber
where the king would sit
and make his decisions.
Welcome, nerds,
to this nerd elysium,
where we will be revealing
which two nerds
will be going to head-to-head
in our first Nerd-Off.
The winner will stay
to compete for the crown
and the right to sit atop...
The throne of games!
[Cheers and applause]
Xander: This is the first time that
I've seen the throne of games,
and it became
a real competition.
There's gonna be blood shed
to get to that chair.
The loser
goes home immediately.
But first, have you come up
with your team names?
Our team is...
The Midas...
- Touch...
- Attack!
There was even a presentation.
It's amazing.
And how did that come about?
We are the gold team,
and the Midas Touch
is the ability
to turn things into gold.
The Touch Attack
is a dungeons & dragons term
for a direct physical attack
that penetrates armor.
Okay, a lot of work
went into that. Thank you.
Purple team.
Standing upon the shoulders
of giants, we are...
All: The Titans of Rigel!
[All snap fingers]
Last time, they just told us.
[Laughter]
Why The Titans of Rigel?
Could you explain that?
We are titans, individually, we
come together to work as a team,
and Rigel is the foot star
from the constellation orion.
And we are standing
on the shoulders of giants
to take our fields
to the next level.
All the past scientists
and philosophers
have propelled us
to this moment.
"Titans" also sounds
more badass than "giants."
And I'm sorry, Curtis,
but it's "rhy-jel."
- Uh, yes.
- Soft "G." Soft "G."
Yeah, soft "g." I know.
[Laughs]
We have your votes right here.
Team Midas Touch Attack...
Katie: I feel like the people
who are on the chopping block
are really Chris and Kayla.
They're seen as these,
sort of, science powerhouses.
By unanimous consent...
Chris, you will be going
to the Nerd-Off.
I'm hoping that the gold team
thinks I'm a threat,
rather than thinking
that I'm the weakest player.
It's a compliment. His own
words, it's a compliment.
He is, you know...
he has a lot of skills,
and we want to take those out
early in the game.
Titans of Rigel...
Your first vote is...
Kelsey.
Second vote...
Third vote...
Brian.
Fourth vote...
Kelsey.
Kelsey: I have a big "X" on my back
just 'cause of what happened yesterday.
It's like,
"man! Again? Oh, joy."
- Kelsey...
- Yes.
You will be going
to the Nerd-Off.
Well, after what happened yesterday,
I have a lot to prove, don't I?
And I'm going to
prove it today.
Kelsey, Chris...
step forward, please.
Bend the knee.
Today, you will be tested on your
knowledge of all things fantasy.
Bobby, the broom!
[Laughs]
I know that broom!
Kayla: Oh, wow.
Behold...
The nerd bolt.
[Laughter]
Today, you are going to be
doing battle in the skies...
Like Quidditch!
Curtis: In a game we call...
"Nerdditch."
[Laughter, applause]
I'm a huge "Harry Potter" fan.
I'm a Hufflepuff.
You have three hours
to prepare.
Whoever loses will become
he who must not be nerdy.
[Laughter]
May the best nerd win.
Kelsey: I'm gonna prove
that I deserve to be here.
I may not be an engineer
or a scientist,
but that doesn't mean that I can't
win this entire competition.
This is pretty much the worst challenge
for me, I would have to say.
I am not a fan of fantasy.
Are you guys familiar
with "Game of Thrones"?
Not the books.
I've read all the books.
I haven't seen the show.
Okay.
I think to be a nerd,
you need to have a passion
in something
that can be useful to society,
so that's why I'm actually
a fan of science fiction,
which is "Star Trek."
I don't think that he has
the ability to compete.
He knows Sci-Fi.
Mary Kate: He's got
that engineering mind.
But fantasy?
He's in the dark completely.
Like, this is exactly
how we planned it.
We rolled the 20.
If we get rid of Chris on their
team, we remove their foundation,
and you get rid of the foundation
of a building, it crumbles.
Midas Touch Attack!
[Both cheer]
Kelsey: I don't know.
When they say "fantasy,"
I'm like, "what kind of fantasy?
Where is the fantasy?
Whose fantasy?"
Xander: Kelsey's definitely
the luna Lovegood.
She's off in her own world.
She's a little bit spacy.
I wouldn't be surprised if she
showed up with radish earrings.
How do you think they're gonna go with,
like, maybe, traditional fairy tales?
'Cause I have
a very good knowledge of...
But that's what makes her
so dangerous,
is that you don't know
what's gonna happen.
Brian: Terry pratchett...
- how are you guys on Terry pratchett?
- Got to learn it.
Chris: I'm not panicking.
The last time
I've had to study something
was when I was trying to figure out
how to solve a rubik's cube...
I'm just going to try
to put as much
random information in my head
as possible.
And it requires a lot of focus,
so I'll probably be using
those same resources
to help me out
in this challenge.
What about "Harry Potter"? Where
are you guys on "Harry Potter"?
Not good.
I've read all of the books,
but it's just been years.
Yes, 2007... I was
at space camp that year, yeah.
The results of this Nerd-Off
can really change
the dynamics of the team.
If we lose Chris,
we lose our strongest player.
It could be
a huge gravitational well
that's just gonna send us
flying in the wrong direction.
Brian: Getting put in the Nerd-Off
is by no means a death sentence.
This is not facedown in
the guillotine, slice it off.
It's time to prove yourself.
Jack: Mindy the pom pom girl
is probably the cutest girl
at this moment.
I'd take her out
to dinner and a movie.
[Singsong voice] That would be a
very nerdy relationship. Whoo-hoo!
Welcome to
our first Nerd-Off...
a magical game of Nerdditch.
After correctly answering
a fantasy-based question,
you will have the chance
to fly on a broom down a course
while attempting
to throw vials of potion
into cauldrons
of varying point value.
The nerd with
the highest number of points
at the end of five rounds
is the winner.
The loser is banished forever.
Kayla:
Who knows who's gonna win?
This is going to be
up to whichever God out there
you believe in...
or non-God or whatever.
We come to our first question.
Dude, it's easy... Nimbus.
It's a broom. Duh.
Reveal your answer.
You are both correct.
The answer is Nimbus.
Kelsey,
you will be flying first.
[Cheers and applause]
[Dramatic accent]
Nerdditch is about to begin!
Kelsey: I don't throw potions
into a cauldron
as part of my daily routine,
so I'm just gonna aim for one of
the big ones right off the start.
Go!
[Contestants cheering]
Curtis:
She's approaching the 100.
She's passed.
She must be eyeing one of the
larger-point-value cauldrons,
though she does have
up to six potion vials to throw.
[Indistinct shouting]
Oh! She just missed!
It just went by too fast.
Jack: I was not expecting so
much of a dexterity component.
Calculating relativity
is hard on paper.
Imagine calculating relativity
while flying on a broomstick.
Kayla: Chris! Fly! Katie: Whoo!
Chris is gonna be
a pivotal first elimination.
Ready...
If he loses, we took out
a huge player right away.
Set... If he wins,
we're gonna fear him a whole lot
more than we already do.
Go!
Fly, nerd! Fly!
[Contestants cheering]
Chris is preparing
his first vial,
looking at
that 100-point cauldron.
[Cheering]
- That was a direct hit.
- It was a direct hit, by gosh.
Attempting the 500.
And it's off the rim!
[Cheers and applause]
Very good flight.
Boom goes the dynamite!
Now the score is Chris 100
and Kelsey with 0.
And now the second question.
Zack: Is that a joke?
I can't believe
he's asking these questions.
Reveal!
The correct answer
is "slightly alive."
How?
What color
is the red fire truck?
That was the level
of the question here.
This is crazy.
I'm sorry, Chris.
False is incorrect.
Kelsey, you get to fly.
Yay! [Laughs]
You shall not pass!
[Boom!]
That was my staff. Boom!
Curtis: Great chance here
to put some points on the board
and pull ahead of Chris.
Go!
Bobby: There she goes, Curtis.
Xander: Ganbatte!
Curtis: Here she goes.
She's approaching
the 100-point cauldrons, and...
Oh! She just missed it!
Bobby: That was so close.
Oh! And she missed the 250!
That's gonna hurt.
Missing was pretty frustrating,
and "kirai desu."
You know, I don't like it.
You know,
I don't like it at all.
Next question.
Brian: If I were in
their position, I'd be like,
"okay, I have to study
'Game of Thrones, '"
but I'm also really
obsessive-compulsive about spoilers,
and I wouldn't want to spoil
myself just to win a challenge.
The correct answer
is knight of the king's guard.
Kelsey,
you are about to fly again.
Okay, but this is the problem...
she needs actually a score.
Ready... Set... Go!
Bobby: Okay, Kelsey.
Curtis: She's reaching
early for the vials.
And she hasn't even...
now she's approaching.
Oh! And she misses!
She got one!
She got one... 100.
Kelsey is now tied with Chris.
Oh! Just misses a 250!
Ohh!
Kelsey has just pulled ahead
350 to 100!
[Speaking Japanese] Awesome!
This is the last question.
Chris, you must answer correctly
for a chance to win.
One cauldron, pewter.
One plain, pointed hat.
One owl, any breed of choice.
One copy of "magical theory"
by adalbert waffling.
Come on, Kelsey.
Chris knows a lot, but fantasy?
Chris doesn't even know
what a dungeon master is.
How do you get into Nerdvana
without knowing what
a flippin' dungeon master does?
So, this is the perfect
opportunity to get rid of him.
Reveal.
And the answer is
one owl, any breed of choice.
You will both go flying.
Chris, you'll fly first.
The only reason I'm in this game
is because I studied my butt off
when it came to
"Harry Potter" questions.
[Contestants cheering]
Xander: If we lose Chris, it would
be a huge blow to the titans.
We're putting a lot of stock
in him keeping us together.
Set... Go!
Katie: It's Titan time!
[Contestants cheering]
Josh: The result
of this Nerd-Off is big.
If they lose Chris,
they lose their leader.
We want them to be in chaos.
Ready... Set... Go!
- And he's off, Curtis.
- Yep.
Chris is down by 250 points
and has to make it up here
on the final run.
And... He throws.
- Misses the 100.
[Chanting] Chris! Chris! Chris!
- Misses the 200.
And it's 500! An amazing shot!
And Chris has taken the lead!
Chris has risen from the
cauldron of his father's bones
and the blood of his enemies
like lord Voldemort.
Kelsey, you're gonna
have to make 250 points.
Mary Kate:
If Chris ends up winning,
just like Newton's third law
of motion...
with every action, there's an
opposite and equal reaction...
and I'm just worried about the
reaction that we're gonna get.
Let's do it!
Go!
You can see the concentration
in her face now, Bobby.
She's really focused.
Bobby: She's serious this time.
She's already taken
one of the vials out.
She's approaching
the 100 cauldrons.
And she got one in!
Kelsey's one cauldron
away from victory!
And she missed the second!
She'll have one more chance
at this 500-point cauldron.
And she missed the third!
Kelsey has come up short,
which means, Chris,
you have won this Nerd-Off!
[Cheers and applause] Oh, my.
I'm going back to Nerdvana,
and I'm going for the gold team.
You will receive Texas justice.
Jack: Chris, you swallowed
a bottle of Felix felicis.
That's the luck potion
in "Harry Potter."
Kelsey, while the sun may set
for you here at Nerdvana,
we know that you will always be one
with the land of the rising sun.
So fly off, Kelsey, to all that
the future will hold for you.
I can't wait. [Chuckles]
Brian: The Titans of Rigel...
we stand on the shoulders
of our predecessors,
and Kelsey becomes
one of our predecessors.
Ja ne! Minasan,
arigatou gozaimasu!
Ganbarimasu!
Brian: It's an honor for us to be
able to stand on her shoulder.
On the other hand,
nobody wants to be the shoulder.
Kayla: Being able
to actually talk to people,
get out of my computer
and my books,
it's just
such a fascinating experience.
And these are
all amazing people.
And Nerdvana was like
its own mini-world.
You know, "chiisai sekai"...
its own "little, tiny world."
And, oh, my goodness,
what a world to be in.
[Speaking Japanese]
Do your best, my new friends!
She was unique.
She was.
[Beep] [Roaring]
[Both laugh]
Sync & corrections by No1
www.addic7ed.com.